flysaa.com 2019-09-01

# SAA Privacy Policy - South African Airways

We may collect and process the following categories of personal information shown below. ** **

**Identity information**

We may record your name, gender and date of birth, your nationality and passport information.

**Contact details**

SAA will process your address, telephone number and email address. We may also record your sign in details and other information you fill out on your personal account or registration form, when you create a personal account or register for a service. For business travelers, we may also collect information relating to your company, such as company name and business location.

**Reservations details**

When you make a reservation or book a flight with us, we will process details about your flight, prices and the date of your reservation or booking. We will also process information regarding upgrades, extra baggage, products you purchase, preferred payment method, billing information, transaction and credit information.

**Travel details**

When you travel with us, we process information in relation to your journey. This includes details on your itinerary, (online) check-in, boarding pass and your travel companions. We will also process details of any medical needs, dietary requests and any additional assistance you require.

**Voyager membership**

When you become a member of our loyalty program, we process your membership number, miles, rewards and benefits, level of membership and other information related to your membership. You can update most of your personal details yourself at any time by logging into your Voyager profile [here](https://www.flysaa.com/za/en/voyagerLogin.secured).

**Communication details**

When you send us an email or chat with us online, we register your communication with us. When you call us, our customer support will register your questions or complaints in our database. We may also record telephone calls for training purposes or to prevent or combat fraud.

**Sensitive data**

Generally, we try to limit the circumstances where we collect and process sensitive personal data. Examples of where we may collect and process ‘sensitive personal data’ includes the following:

  * You have requested specific medical assistance from us and/or an airport operator, such as the provision of wheelchair assistance or oxygen.
  * You have sought clearance from us to fly with a medical condition or because you are more than 28 weeks pregnant.
  * You have otherwise chosen to provide such information to us or it has been passed onto us by a third party such as the travel agent through which you made your booking.
  * Biometric information (for example, facial recognition) may be collected during the security clearance process prior to, and after, flying with us.

In addition, you may have requested services (such as a meal) which is not ’sensitive data’ but may imply or suggest your religion, health or other information.

**Cookies and similar technologies**

When you use our website or mobile apps we collect information via cookies and similar technologies. For more information please read our cookie policy on the website or mobile app you use.

**To provide our services to you**

To handle your reservations and bookings and to fulfill your travel arrangements and purchases, we need to process most of the information described above. For example, we need your name, passport number and other identifying information to issue your ticket. To inform you about changes in departure times, we need your contact details. In addition, to ensure that you receive the required care, we require your specified medical needs.

**To facilitate our loyalty programmes**

To let you or your company benefit from the discounts and rewards under our loyalty programmes, we use your membership information and your booking information.

**To provide our online services and mobile apps to you**

  * For example, we use your name and flight details when you check-in for your flight with our app.
  * To ease your use of our online services or apps, we may analyze the data we collect when you use our digital media and combine it with information collected via cookies and similar technologies. For example, to understand which digital channel (email, social media) or device (desktop, tablet or mobile) you prefer, so we can restrict our communication to that channel or device.

**To communicate with you**  
We use your contact details to communicate with you, answer your questions or handle your complaints.

**For statistical research**

  * We use automatic tools to perform statistical research into general trends regarding the use of our services, loyalty programs, websites, apps and social media and the behavior and preferences of our customers and users.
  * To perform our research, we may merge and analyze the different types of data as described above. We will only use aggregated data and do not use name, email address or other directly identifying information. We may also combine such aggregated data with information we receive from our group companies or from public sources. We will not use sensitive data for this statistical research without your consent.
  * Statistical research helps us to develop better services and offerings, to improve our loyalty programs, to provide more responsive customer support and to improve the design and content of our websites and mobile apps.

**For direct marketing purposes**

  * We may use your personal information to send you newsletters, promotions or other marketing communications.
  * Categories of data. To understand what is relevant to you, we may use automatic tools to analyze your personal information. For this purpose, we may use and combine the information described above. We may also combine such aggregated data with information we receive from our group companies or from public sources. Without your consent we will not use sensitive data for this statistical research.
  * We use the results of our analysis to tailor our marketing communications to your specific interests and preferences. For example, if our analysis shows that you may be interested in certain types of travel or a specific destination, we may customize our newsletter and websites with offers and content that we believe will be relevant to you.
  * We may use different channels for our marketing communications, such as e-mail, apps, social media and your personal online account.
  * For facilitating immigration formalities, entering the territory of a State or fulfillment of statutory obligations 

You can update most of your personal details yourself at any time by [logging into your account](https://www.flysaa.com/about-us/leading-carrier/newsletter/update-your-details). You can unsubscribe from mailing lists at any time, by clicking the unsubscribe link on any of our emails, or by emailing us directly at:

South Africa [webhelp@flysaa.com](mailto:WebHelp@flysaa.com)

Rest of Africa [africahelp@flysaa.com](mailto:africahelp@flysaa.com)

UK [ukhelp@flysaa.com](mailto:UKHelp@flysaa.com)

Americas [ushelp@flysaa.com](mailto:USHelp@flysaa.com)

Europe [euhelp@flysaa.com](mailto:euhelp@flysaa.com)

Australia [auhelp@flysaa.com](mailto:auhelp@flysaa.com) 

Middle East [mesalessupport@flysaa.com](mailto:mesalessupport@flysaa.com) 

**The right to be informed**

Individuals have the right to be informed about the collection and use of their personal data.

**The right of access**

Individuals have the right to access their personal data and supplementary information.

**The right to rectification**

The right for individuals to have inaccurate personal data rectified, or completed if it is incomplete.

**The right to erasure**

A right for individuals to have personal data deleted. Also known as ‘the right to be forgotten’.

**The right to restrict  processing**

Individuals have the right to request the restriction or suppression of their personal data.

**The right to data portability**

Allows individuals to obtain and reuse their personal data for their own purposes across different services.

**The right to object**

Individuals have the right to object to:

  * Processing based on legitimate interests or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority (including profiling)
  * Direct marketing (including profiling); and
  * Processing for purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics.

**Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling.**

Applies to all automated individual decision-making and profiling.

**Legitimate Interests**

As a commercial airline and travel provider SAA has a legitimate business interest to use the personal information we collect to offer an effective service and carry out our business.  

**Compliance with legal obligations**

There are situations where SAA is subject to a legal obligation and needs to use your personal information to comply with those obligations.

**To protect the vital interest of you or another person**

There are situations where we may need to use your personal information to protect the vital interests of you or another person.

**Consent**

Alternatively, we may collect and use your personal information where you have given your specific consent to us doing so. If the basis of our processing your data is consent, you can withdraw your consent to such processing at any time. However, if you withdraw this consent, in some circumstances, it may mean we will not be able to provide all or parts of the services you have requested from us and you will not be able to cancel your booking or obtain a refund of any charges you have paid.
